Guide to the Wunderman Archives, 1946-2010 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Materials, 1946-2003 and undated, (122 boxes)
  - Wunderman Cato Johnson (WCJ) (Box 108)
    - Popeil; Tut Totes; Vista Marketing; ICS; Time Life Books; Merrill Lynch. Undated. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: 10:00 (Box 108)
    - Popeil; J. C. Penney; Time Life Books; Operation Welcome Home; CIT Financial; Columbia House; Hills Pet Products; Showtime; DuPont; AT&T; Time Magazine; American Express. 1993. Umatic. TRT: 60:00 (Box 108)
    - Presenting to Win. Undated. Umatic. PAL. TRT: 30:00 (Box 108)
    - Reel Commerciales: Puerto Rico (Frito Lay); Chile (Agrogas, Ford); Peru (Solventa). Undated. Umatic. TRT: 20:00 (Box 108)
    - Results Speak Volumes. 1996. Umatic. TRT: 5:41 (Box 108)
    - Results Speak Volumes. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 7:00(5 copies) (Box 108)
  - Wunderman Cato Johnson (WCJ) (Box 109)
    - Results Speak Volumes. Undated. Umatic. PAL. TRT: 7:00(2 copies) (Box 109)
    - Results Speak Volumes. Undated. VHS. PAL. TRT: 7:00 (Box 109)
    - Roz Gohagen: Direct Mail Production. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 20:00 (Box 109)
    - Sales Promotion Training Session: Gillette; Taco Bell; Kodak; Certs; USPS; CBS. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 5:00 (Box 109)
    - Saturday Night Live: Larry the Lobster. 2001. VHS. PAL. TRT: 10:00 (Box 109)
    - Saturday Night Live: Larry the Lobster. 2000. VHS. TRT: 10:00 (Box 109)
    - Sears; AT&T; American Express. 1997; Umatic. TRT: 8:17(3 tapes) (Box 109)
    - Sears; Columbia House; Citibank; Showtime; AT&T. 1999. Umatic. TRT: 6:00 (Box 109)
    - Sears; Orangina; American Express; DuPont. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 5:00 (Box 109)
    - Show reel. 1996. VHS. NTSC. TRT: 30:00 (Box 109)
    - Show reel 1 hour loop. 1999. Umatic. TRT: 60:00(2 copies) (Box 109)
    - Show reel: Master. 1995. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: 15:00 (Box 109)
  - Wunderman Cato Johnson (WCJ) (Box 110)
    - Show reel. 1995. VHS. NTSC. TRT: 15:53 (Box 110)
    - Show reel. 1995. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: 15:53 (Box 110)
    - Show reel: Prodigy; Columbia House; Breakfast Meeting; Apple; AT&T; Pepsi. 1995. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: 30:00 (Box 110)
    - Show reel #1: Sony Card; Worldnet; AT&T; Oxford Health; Geocities; Showtime; Quicken. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 110)
    - Show reel #2: Geocities; AT&T Worldnet. Undated. VHS. TRT: 10:00 (Box 110)
    - Sony Card; Geocities; Showtime; Quicken. 2000. Umatic. TRT: 4:00 (Box 110)
    - Spot reel: Agrogas; Enagas. Undated. VHS. TRT: 5:00 (Box 110)
    - Spot reel: American Express; AT&T; Orangina; Columbia House; DuPont; Showtime. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 8:48 (Box 110)
    - Spot reel: Columbia House; American Express; British Airways; AT&T; Showtime; Orangina; BMW Milan; Dion Eggs; Compagna Casa Protegida. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 110)
    - Spot reel: Columbia House; N. Y. Rangers; AT&T; American Express; Operation Welcome Home; DuPont; Showtime. 1995. Umatic. TRT: 10:00(2 copies) (Box 110)
    - Spots: New York; Showtime; Starz; NCTA. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 20:00 (Box 110)
    - Super Bowl reel: 70 spots. 1998. Umatic. TRT: 60:00 (Box 110)
    - Sun Direct; SIS Insurance; Southern Cross (Australian spots). Undated. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: 4:15 (Box 110)
    - Sun Direct; SIS Insurance; Southern Cross; Caltex (Australian spots). Undated. Betacam SP. TRT: 10:00 (Box 110)
    - Taking Care of Business. Undated. VHS. TRT: 29:00 (Box 110)
    - Time; Columbia; Time Life Books; Sports Illustrated; Fortune Magazine. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 30:00 (Box 110)
  - Wunderman Cato Johnson (WCJ) (Box 111)
    - Time historical roll out creative. 1989. Umatic. TRT: 30:00 (Box 111)
    - Untitled commercial. Undated. VHS. TRT: 120:00 (Box 111)
    - Video Learning Systems: 30 Ways to Make More Time. Undated. Umatic. PAL. TRT: 30:00 (Box 111)
    - Visa + Mastercard. 1998. VHS. TRT: 30:00 (Box 111)
    - Volkswagen; Levi's. 1997. Umatic. TRT: 1:00 (Box 111)
    - WCJ Auckland: Sun Direct; WEL Energy Group. 1995. VHS. NTSC. TRT: 2:15 (Box 111)
    - WCJ Brazil: 80 Anos Sociedad de Cultura Artistica. 1993. VHS. TRT: 15:00 (Box 111)
    - WCJ Brazil: CMX reel 4. Undated. Betacam SP. TRT: 10:00 (Box 111)
    - WCJ Brazil: Operation Robin Hood. 1993. VHS. TRT: 120:00 (Box 111)
    - WCJ Brazil: Port Folio. Undated. VHS. TRT: 60:00 (Box 111)
    - WCJ Chile: 14 spots. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 111)
    - WCJ Italy: Agency Showtime reel. 1994. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 111)
    - WCJ Johannesburg; WCJ CopenhagenUndated. Betacam SP. TRT: 10:00 (Box 111)
    - WCJ Madrid: La autopista del mar; mai unidos que nunca. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 20:00 (Box 111)
    - WCJ Milan: Agency presentation. 1994. Umatic. PAL. TRT: 10:00 (Box 111)
    - WCJ Milan: BMW; Xerox; Hatu. 1997. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: 10:00(2 copies) (Box 111)
    - WCJ Paris: Bingo; Dillings. 1996. VHS. TRT: 20:00 (Box 111)
  - Wunderman Cato Johnson (WCJ) (Box 112)
    - WCJ San Juan?: Parque del recuerdo; Agrogas radio. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 112)
    - WCJ San Juan: Compagna Casa Protegido de Burgos; Stayfree Ultra. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 112)
    - WCJ Thailand: UTV. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 0:30 (Box 112)
    - Worldwide Creative 60 minute loop. 2000. Umatic. TRT: 60:00 (Box 112)
    - Worldwide Creative. 2000. Umatic. TRT: 11:30(2 copies) (Box 112)
    - Wunderman Part 1 and 2. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 27:00 (Box 112)
    - Wunderman Part 1: The Man, the Myth, the Legend. Undated. VHS. TRT: 14:55(8 copies) (Box 112)
    - Wunderman Part 2: The Agency, the People, the Dreams. Undated. VHS. TRT: 12:07(8 copies) (Box 112)
  - Wunderman Cato Johnson (WCJ) (Box 113)
    - Wunderman Part 2: The Agency, the People, the Dreams. Undated. VHS. TRT: 12:07(3 copies) (Box 113)
    - Wunderman Cato Johnson and Partners. 1993. VHS. TRT: 5:00 (Box 113)
    - Xerox; American Express; Ericsson. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 2:30 (Box 113)
    - Xerox; Ericsson; Sears Home Central; U. S. Army; AT&T; Oxford Health; USPS; First USA. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 20:00(2 copies) (Box 113)
    - Xerox; Ericsson; Sears Home Central; U. S. Army; AT&T; Oxford Health; USPS; First USA. Undated. VHS. TRT: 20:00 (Box 113)
    - Xerox; AT&T. Undated. VHS. TRT: 30:00 (Box 113)
    - Ya Gotta Wear Shades. 1994. Umatic. TRT: 2:00 (Box 113)
  - Wunderman Ricotta & Kline
    - Advdertising Skills Workshop: 18 spots. 1978. Umatic. TRT: 50:00 (Box 113)
    - Agency reel. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 113)
    - AT&T; Dow Jones Report. 1979. Umatic. TRT: 1:00 (Box 113)
    - Cassette: NYTel; Time Magazine; Money Magazine; Grolier; Time Life Books; Columbia House. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 11:30 (Box 113)
    - CIT reel. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 113)
    - Florida: Supervalue. 1985. Umatic. TRT: 3:00 (Box 113)
    - Jeff Scher's special cassette of funny commercials. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 113)
    - L. L. Bean; Phoenix House. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 30:00 (Box 113)
  - Wunderman Ricotta & Kline (Box 114)
    - History of WRK Luncheon. 1982. Audiocassette. TRT: 90:00 (Box 114)
    - Mike Slosberg, Advertising Skills Workshop. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 30:00 (Box 114)
    - Modern Time clip from Charlie Chaplin; Larry the Lobster. 1986. VHS. TRT: 30:00 (Box 114)
    - Modern Times clip; Sleeper clips; Tempo; Time Life Books; Sports Illustrated; Larry the Lobster. 1986. Umatic. TRT: 20:00 (Box 114)
    - Mort Kasman: Winter Windows; Government. 1980. Umatic. TRT: 3:00 (Box 114)
    - Nancy Jones: Old West; Civil War; Columbia House; L. L. Bean; Pert; Vietnam. 1985. Umatic. TRT: 20:00 (Box 114)
    - Off Again globe wrap. 1985. Umatic. TRT: 2:00 (Box 114)
    - Presentation M. Slosberg: 33 spots. 1981. Umatic. TRT: 36:00 (Box 114)
    - Produced commercials: Money Magazine; Sports Illustrated; Hospital Corporation of America. 1985. Umatic. TRT: 12:00 (Box 114)
    - Production year sample reel: 13 spots. 1979. Umatic. TRT: 30:00 (Box 114)
    - Radio spots: Fortune Magazine; Geico; Merrill Lynch; Time; Spring Magazine. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 60:00 (Box 114)
    - RVI Presentation, John Stevenson, Direct Response TV Segment. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 60:00 (Box 114)
    - Spring Direct Marketing Workshop, Maxeen Schonfeld presentation. 1982. Umatic. TRT: 20:00 (Box 114)
    - TP dictionary (Fisler). Undated. Umatic. TRT: 3:00 (Box 114)
    - Training Cassette: Classic direct marketing; general advertising; direct response TV; contrast cases. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 60:00 (Box 114)
  - Wunderman Ricotta & Kline (Box 115)
    - Vista presentation. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 115)
    - What Is Direct Marketing? Presentation. 21 spots. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 60:00 (Box 115)
    - Woody Allen's Sleeper: Robot clip. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 20:00 (Box 115)
    - Woody Allen's Sleeper: Tailor clip. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 20:00 (Box 115)
  - Wunderman Worldwide
    - Compilation. 1992. VHS. TRT: 15:00 (Box 115)
    - Compiled spots: 20 commercials. 1989. Umatic. TRT: 60:00 (Box 115)
    - Creative examples for new business pitch: USAID Caribbean tourism. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 20:00 (Box 115)
    - Demo reel: Whitehall; Kentucky Fried Chicken; Colgate; Frito Lay (most Spanish language commercials). 1995. Umatic. TRT: 60:00 (Box 115)
    - Diet Mountain Dew; AT&T. 1993. Umatic. TRT: 0:45 (Box 115)
    - Gadgets on Parade. 1989. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 115)
    - High-Tech Show, tape 1 of 2. 1993. Umatic. TRT: 60:00 (Box 115)
    - Hills's Pet Products; Operation Welcome Home. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 115)
    - John Sanders, Corporate Communications Package. 1991. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 115)
    - NYNEX; Manufacturers Hanover; N. Y. Telephone; Garraway; Caesar's. 1987. Audiocassette. TRT: 10:00(2 copies) (Box 115)
    - Time; Sports Illustrated; Fortune. 1987. Audiocassette. TRT: 10:00(2 copies) (Box 115)
  - Wunderman Worldwide (Box 116)
    - Master: Time Life Books compilation. 1988. Umatic. TRT: 60:00 (Box 116)
    - Ref School; Sneak Preview. 1989. Umatic. TRT: 5:00(3 copies) (Box 116)
    - Spirit; To Your Success; Oui Merci. 1989. Umatic. TRT: 4:00 (Box 116)
    - Spots; international commercials for Time Life Books, Sports Illustrated, Time, CBS Video, PTT Nederland, Multiple Schlerosis, Monier, Weight Watchers. 1988. Umatic. TRT: 60:00 (Box 116)
    - Tut Totes; AT&T. 1992. Umatic. TRT: 5:00 (Box 116)
    - U. K. commercials: Gnomes; Shock Absorbers; Yorkshire TV. 1990. VHS. NTSC. TRT: 14:00 (Box 116)
    - Video Focus. 1993. VHS. TRT: 12:36 (Box 116)
    - Wunderman Sydney, South Africa commercials1988. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: 4:30 (Box 116)
    - Wunderman Sydney: Wunderman World awards, Monier Umbrella. 1988. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: 1:00 (Box 116)
    - Wunderman Sydney: Y&R Our awards; Monier Redland. 1988. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: 0:15 (Box 116)
    - Wunderman Thailand: Thanacity, UTV. Undated. VHS. NTSC. TRT: 15:00 (Box 116)
    - Wunderman Worldwide and Partners. 1992. Umatic. TRT: 6:00 (Box 116)
    - Wunderman Worldwide and Partners. 1993. Umatic. TRT: 6:00 (Box 116)
    - Wunderman Worldwide awards, U. S. version. Undated. VHS. NTSC. TRT: 60:00 (Box 116)
  - Xerox (Box 117)
    - Corporate: Snow; Rain. 1995. Umatic. TRT: 1:00 (Box 117)
    - Digital Copiers: Mousetrap. 1997. Umatic. TRT: 6:30 (Box 117)
    - Digital Copiers: Two Worlds video. 1998. Umatic. TRT: 7:52 (Box 117)
    - Document Centre video. 1997. Umatic. TRT: 7:07 (Box 117)
    - Document Centre: Two Worlds. 1998. Umatic. TRT: 17:00 (Box 117)
    - Mousetrap. 1997. Umatic. TRT: 1:00 (Box 117)
    - Mousetrap. Undated. VHS. TRT: 1:00 (Box 117)
    - Mousetrap; Document Centre video. 1997. Umatic. TRT: 8:37 (Box 117)
    - Mousetrap; New Mneumonic Dealer Tag. 1997. Umatic. TRT: 2:00 (Box 117)
    - Side by Side. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 0:30 (Box 117)
    - Side by Side. Undated. VHS. TRT: 0:30 (Box 117)
    - The Perfect 10: Ten Guiding Principles to Strengthen Customer Service. 1993. Audiocassette. TRT: Undetermined. (Box 117)
    - Two Worlds. 1998. VHS. TRT: 9:22(2 copies) (Box 117)
    - WCJ London. Undated. VHS. TRT: 30:00 (Box 117)
  - Young & Rubicam (Y&R) (Box 118)
    - 4 Car and Truck Spots. Undated. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: 10:00 (Box 118)
    - 30 Ways to Make More Time. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 30:00(2 copies) (Box 118)
    - 30 Ways to Make More Time. Undated. VHS. PAL. TRT: 30:00 (Box 118)
    - 75 Years Young. 1996. VHS. TRT: 15:00 (Box 118)
    - Adbank Cable Spots: Comedy Central; ESPN; HBO; 1-800-OK-Cable.. 1994. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 118)
    - Adbank Cable Spots: 27 spots. 1995 Jan. Umatic. TRT: 20:00 (Box 118)
    - Adbank Cable Spots: 13 spots. 1995 Feb. Umatic. TRT: 5:00 (Box 118)
    - Adbank Cable Spots: 28 spots. 1995 Mar. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 118)
    - Adbank Cable Spots: 22 spots. 1995 May. Umatic. TRT: 20:00 (Box 118)
    - Advertising Skills Workshop: Problem Solving Strategies, The Synectics Approach.. Undated. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: 28:00 (Box 118)
    - Alex Kroll: Strategy for the 90s. 1991. Umatic. TRT: 29:55(2 copies) (Box 118)
    - American Express; Nationwide; Showtime; AT&T; Army; Apple. Undated. VHS. TRT: 10:00 (Box 118)
    - Apollo 13 (Leadership clips). Undated. Umatic. TRT: 30:00 (Box 118)
    - Banking reel. Undated. VHS. TRT: 30:00 (Box 118)
  - Young & Rubicam (Y&R) (Box 119)
    - Beach; Teen Date. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 2:00 (Box 119)
    - Best of Get Smartest, highlights from KCA conference. 1999. VHS. TRT: 16:00 (Box 119)
    - Best of Y&R Worldwide. 1994. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 119)
    - Best of Y&R Worldwide. 1996. Umatic. TRT: 15:00 (Box 119)
    - Best of Y&R Worldwide. 1997. Umatic. TRT: 40:00 (Box 119)
    - Best of Y&R Worldwide. 1997. Umatic. TRT: 40:35 (Box 119)
    - Best spots of December. 1997. Umatic. TRT: 20:00 (Box 119)
    - Cannes Lions. 1999. Umatic. TRT: 120:00(2 tapes) (Box 119)
    - Children advertising. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 30:00 (Box 119)
    - Combo reel: 21 spots. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 30:00 (Box 119)
    - Communication Arts. 1999. Umatic. TRT: 60:00 (Box 119)
    - Creative Leap: Leo Tolstoy. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 18:00 (Box 119)
    - Cuando. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 1:00 (Box 119)
    - Effective Presentation Workshop: Presenting to Win. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 40:00(2 copies) (Box 119)
  - Young & Rubicam (Y&R) (Box 120)
    - Effective Presentation Workshop: Presenting to Win. Undated. VHS. TRT: 30:00 (Box 120)
    - Effective Presentation Workshop: President's Report. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 30:00 (Box 120)
    - Fast food reel. 1994. Umatic. TRT: 60:00 (Box 120)
    - Fuel and coal advertising spots. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 120)
    - Good Advertising commercials (Alan H. Zwiebel). Undated. Umatic. TRT: 60:00 (Box 120)
    - How to Recognize Good Advertising: Advertisement reel. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 29:00 (Box 120)
    - How to Recognize Good Advertising: Presentation reel. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 60:00 (Box 120)
    - International Supermarkets Review. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 60:00 (Box 120)
    - Latest and Greatest. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 120)
    - Mitch Kurz, Y&R annual meeting. 1994. Umatic. TRT: 15:00 (Box 120)
    - New business reel. 1997. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 120)
    - Partnership meeting: Print show and television reel. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 20:00 (Box 120)
    - Peter Georgescu interview, CNN Pinnacle show. 1996. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: 40:00 (Box 120)
    - Peter Georgescu interview, CNN Pinnacle show. 1996. Umatic. PAL. TRT: 40:00 (Box 120)
    - Post Office; Merrill Lynch; KFC; Excedrin; Johnson & Johnson. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 120)
    - Power of the Mail. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 120)
  - Young & Rubicam (Y&R) (Box 121)
    - Promotion Marketing: The Action Arm of Marketing. Undated. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: 60:00 (Box 121)
    - Reel of the Month. 1996 June. Umatic. TRT: 40:00 (Box 121)
    - Reel of the Month. 1996 Oct. Umatic. TRT: 40:00 (Box 121)
    - Showcasing the INC Creative Product. 1999. Betacam SP. TRT: 5:00 (Box 121)
    - Skyscraper. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 1:30 (Box 121)
    - The One Show. 1999. Umatic. TRT: 120:00(2 tapes) (Box 121)
    - Trash Worries; Bar Code Forest. 1999. Umatic. TRT: 1:00 (Box 121)
    - Y&R/WCJ Partnership Creative Reel, prepared for Dow Jones. 1998. Umatic. TRT: 10:00 (Box 121)
  - Zeneca Pharmaceuticals
    - Accolate: No Boundaries. 1997. Umatic. TRT: 0:30(2 copies) (Box 121)
    - Accolate: No Boundaries. 1997. VHS. TRT: 0:30 (Box 121)
    - Discover/Family Circle. 1997. Umatic. TRT: 1:30 (Box 121)
  - Wunderman Worldwide
    - Mike Becker's Toronto Speech. 1989. 1" video reel. TRT: Undetermined. (Box 121)
    - Phoenix House: Drug Prevention. 1984. 1" video reel. TRT: 0:30 (Box 121)
  - Wunderman International. The Future of Direct Marketing. Undated. 16mm. 1100'TRT: Undetermined. (Box 122)